samlearning.com 2016-04-14

# Privacy Policy | SAM Learning

At SAM Learning Ltd., we take the privacy of our users seriously. This Privacy Statement describes the information we collect on our website and how we use it. This document covers data supplied by individuals. We have a separate policy for student data sent to SAM Learning by, or under the direction of, schools. This is set out in the Student Data Policy Statement.

**What information do we collect and how do we use it?**

We use your IP address (a special number that relates to your internet connection on your computer) to help identify problems with our server and to help administer our website.

Our website uses cookies. A cookie is a small piece of information that a website stores in your computer so that it can remember things about you (such as your preferences) the next time you visit the site. Our cookies do not harm your computer. We use them to improve the performance of the service, personalise your experience of our website and help track your progress.

_Students_  – if you are a student and you register with us independently of your school, we ask you to provide us with personal details like your first name, your surname, your email address, your password, your password question, your password answer, your school year, your year group, your admission number, your mentors, your classes, your date of birth, your interests and whether you are a boy or a girl. Sometimes this information will already have been provided to us by your parents/guardians or teachers. We also keep records of the marks you have scored in the various learning exercises. We use this information to monitor your progress and analyse your learning needs. We will also use your personal data for the purposes of administration, operation of the service, business development, advertising and marketing. We may use demographic and profile data to tailor your experience of our website and to produce statistics which may be used by your school to help manage learning. We may disclose your marks to your parents/guardians, teachers and school as part of the service.

We aggregate the marks scored by students for the purpose of our internal statistical analysis and research.

We will use your email address to send you the SAM Learning newsletter, which will keep you informed of changes and improvements to the website. The newsletter may contain promotional offers from third parties. It will be sent to you by email no more than once a week. From time to time, we also offer promotions relating to special areas of interest. At any time, you can opt out of receiving the newsletter, or you can opt into the promotions, by ticking the relevant boxes on the ‘My Account’ screen. Whatever you decide, you will not receive more than 4 emails a month from us.

_Teachers_  – if you are a teacher or are registering on behalf of your school, we ask you to provide us with personal details like your name, position, your email address and your interests. We will use this information for the purposes of administration, operation of the service, marketing, sales and business development.

_Parents/guardians_  – if you register for SAM Learning independently of a school, we will ask you to provide us with personal details like your name, your credit/debit card details, your email address and your interests. We will use this information for the purposes of administration, operation of the service, marketing, sales and business development.

We will not sell or disclose your personal information to anyone else without your permission.

We collect statistical information in order to monitor website usage. This helps us to develop our website and the service. We may provide statistical information to third parties. This information will not identify you personally.

**Managing your details**

You may access and update your personal details at any time by clicking on ‘My Account’. Alternatively, if you are a student, you may ask your parent/guardian and/or teacher to do so. Parents/guardians can make changes to their own or their children’s personal details at any time by clicking on ‘My Account’ or by asking the teacher to do so. Teachers can access and update their own or their students’ personal details at any time by clicking on ‘My Account’ or by asking the school administrator to do so. School administrators can access and update their own or their teachers’ or their students’ personal details at any time by clicking on ‘My Account’. Please note that if you delete your records, we will not be able to personalise the service or monitor your progress.

**How we protect your information?**

We store your personal details on a secure server. This means that we use encryption technology and firewalls to protect your information from being accessed by anyone else.

**Making changes**

If we make material changes to the use of your personal data, we shall post details of the changes to this Privacy Statement on our website or send an email to you detailing the changes if they affect you. If you continue to use any service provided by us after you have received notice of the changes, you will be deemed to have consented to the change to the use of your personal data.

**Your consent**

By registering with us and continuing to use the service, you give your consent to the use of your personal data as set out in this Privacy Statement. If you are a parent/guardian and you are registering with us on behalf of your child, you give your consent to our use of your child’s personal data as set out in this Privacy Statement.

**Schools**

We have been advised that one of the reasons schools hold student data is an implied duty to use it for furthering the educational needs of students; this gives schools a right to pass limited information to responsible third parties like SamLearning.com to further this aim.

**How to contact us**

We welcome your views about our Privacy Statement. If you would like to contact us with any queries or comments, please send an email to: [support@samlearning.com](mailto:support@samlearning.com)

**Alternatively, you can write to us at:**

Helpdesk  
SAM Learning Limited  
Fourth Floor,  
29 and 30 High Holborn,  
London,  
WC1V 6AZ
